AMARNATH JAYAKRISHNAN

+1-480-584-7266 | ajayakri@asu.edu | https://www.linkedin.com/in/amarnath-jayakrishnan-4a4813109/

1717 S Dorsey Lane, Apt 2119, Tempe, AZ, 85281

SUMMARY

Highly motivated software developer with 4.8 years of industry experience in backend, frontend as well as machine learning, skilled in object-oriented programming, problem solving methodologies and in-depth knowledge in cloud technologies looking for Summer '22 internship/ co-op opportunities.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Information Technology, Arizona State University

2021-PRESENT

Bachelor of Engineering and Technology, University of Kerala

2012-2016

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Skills: Python, Apache Spark, PLSQL, SQL, Unix, Java, C, C++, C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, PHP, HTML5, DHTML, CSS3, JavaScript, Angular (1.5) JS, React JS, React-native, ES5, ES6, .Net MVC, AJAX, jQuery, JSON, Ext JS, Backbone.js, Node.js, AngularJS2, React, Redux, React-Native, Native Base IDE's and Tools, Eclipse IDE, NetBeans, Dreamweaver, Firebug, Developer Tools, JSfiddle, Restful Services and APIs, XML, DevOps tools, Visual Studio Code, iOS development, Android, SQL, PL/SQL, PostgreSQL, Kubernetes.

Cloud Technologies: Microsoft Azure, AWS, Google Cloud Platform, AWS Terraform, AWS Lambda, AWS API Gateway, AWS AppSync, DynamoDB, Terraform, GraphOL.

Frameworks & Libraries: Django, Flask, Spring MVC, Pandas, NumPy, Spark, NLP, React.JS, Angular.JS, Node.JS, React-Native.

Deployment and Testing Tools: CI/CD pipeline, Git, Selenium, JUnit, Serenity, Docker.

Certifications: AZ-204: Azure Developer Associate, AI-102: Azure AI Engineer Associate, AWS Developer Associate.

Analytics Tools: Tableau, PowerBI, Bokeh.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, Tata Consultancy Services

2016-2021

- Driven the development of core modules and worked with multiple engineering and management stakeholders as a Front-end developer as well as backend developer. Extensively used React.JS, JavaScript, Node.JS, Angular.JS, HTML, CSS etc.
- Experience in ReactJS components, forms, events, keys, router, plus Redux, Flux, Virtual DOM, JSX, etc.
- Worked with frontend libraries, frameworks, and tools such as HTML4/5, CSS2/3, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, Bootstrap and AJAX.
- Worked as backend in REST API development and experience in using Java, Python etc., and frameworks suck as Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Flask, Django etc.
- Adequate experience in database modeling and database architecture of multiple applications.
- Received client appreciation from Commonwealth Bank of Australia and Deutsche Bank.

Mobile Application Developer, University Technology Office at Arizona State University

2021-PRESENT

- Experience in developing scalable mobile applications using React-Native framework. Expertise in React JS and working with React Flux
 architecture. React JS components, Forms, Events, Keys, Router, plus Redux, Animations and Flux concept.
- Good experience in DOM functions, DOM events, DOM collection, DOM navigation, React virtual DOM.
- Experience in React-Native tools like, JSX, JavaScript, Hooks, Redux, Enzyme, ES6, Jest etc.

PROJECTS

- · Learning and Wellness Dashboard: Developed a dashboard which analyses the skills and wellness of employees of an organization using react.js.
- Learning Recommendation system: Developed a ML based learning recommendation system in Unsupervised machine learning by integrating content
 based as well as collaborative recommendation techniques mainly using Pyspark libraries. Developed the REST APIs for the same using python and
 django rest framework.
- ASU Mobile App: Developed Android/ iOS app for Arizona State University students and staff using React-Native framework.

CONTRIBUTIONS

- Django-db-logger: Developed a customized django-db-logger library for capturing logs and customized parameters to the database. (Built a transaction level logging dashboard using this).
- Django email encryption: Developed a customized Django library for email encryption.
- Web Performance: Worked with a team on several web performance optimization such as Code Splitting, Tree Shaking, Chunk Analysis, Code scanning, code optimization, etc.
- Memcache: Developed a memcache library to store the cache to the database in the real-time. This is extensively used for performance optimization.
 Developed a learning recommendation engine using catalogs from Udemy.com for a skill-based/ role-based course recommendation system for TCS employees.
- Improved app store rating, general responsiveness in app, window load, cost savings of mobile application for Arizona State University using React-Native framework.
- Support: Reduce time to resolution, overall volume, and number of unique issues.